<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="api_onuserjoined">
    <title><ph keyref="onUserJoined"/></title>
        <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc">Occurs when a remote user (COMMUNICATION)/ host (LIVE_BROADCASTING) joins the channel.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
   <section id="prototype">
  <p conref="../conref/conref_rtc_api.dita#apidef/onUserJoined"/>
   </section>
   <section id="detailed_desc">
  <ul id="detailed_desc_scene">
   <li>In a communication channel, this callback notifies the application that another user joins the channel. If other users are already in the channel, the SDK also reports to the application on the existing users.</li>
   <li>In a live streaming channel, this callback notifies the app when the host joins the channel. If other hosts are already in the channel, the SDK also reports to the application on the existing hosts. Agora recommends limiting the number of hosts to 17.</li>
        </ul>
  <p>The SDK triggers this callback under one of the following circumstances:</p>
  <ul>
   <li>A remote user/host joins the channel by calling the <apiname keyref="joinChannel1"/> method.</li>
   <li>A remote user switches the user role to the host by calling the <apiname keyref="setClientRole1"/> method after joining the channel.</li>
   <li>A remote user/host rejoins the channel after a network interruption.</li>
   <li>The host injects an online media stream into the channel by calling the <apiname keyref="addInjectStreamUrl"/> method.</li>
        </ul>
      <note outputclass="note" id="note">
     <p>`LIVE_BROADCASTING` profile:</p>
     <ul>
    <li>The host receives this callback when another host joins the channel.</li>
    <li>The audience in the channel receives this callback when a new host joins the channel.</li>
    <li>When a web application joins the channel, the SDK triggers this callback as long as the web application publishes streams.</li>
     </ul>
      </note>
   </section>
   <section id="parameters">
  <title>Parameter</title>
  <parml>
 <plentry id="uid">
<pt>uid</pt>
<pd>The ID of the user or host who joins the channel.</pd>
 </plentry>
 <plentry>
<pt>elapsed</pt>
<pd>Time delay (ms) from the local user calling <apiname keyref="joinChannel1"/> until this callback is triggered.</pd>
 </plentry>
  </parml>
   </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
