<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="api_addpublishstreamurl">
    <title><ph keyref="addPublishStreamUrl"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc">Publishes the local stream to a specified CDN live streaming URL.</ph></shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
   <keywords>
       <indexterm keyref="addPublishStreamUrl" />
   </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <refbody><section id="prototype">

        <p conref="../conref/conref_rtc_api.dita#apidef/addPublishStreamUrl"/>
        </section>
        <section id="detailed_desc">

   <p>After calling this method, you can push media streams in RTMP or RTMPS protocol to the CDN. The SDK triggers the <xref keyref="onRtmpStreamingStateChanged"/> callback on the local client to report the state of adding a local stream to the CDN.</p>
   <note type="attention" id="note">
       <ul>
  <li>Call this method after joining a channel.</li>
  <li>Ensure that you enable the RTMP Converter service before using this function. See Prerequisites in the advanced guide Push Streams to CDN.</li>
  <li>This method takes effect only when you are a host in live interactive streaming.</li>
  <li>This method adds only one stream CDN streaming URL each time it is called. To push multiple URLs, call this method multiple times.</li>
  <li>Agora supports pushing media streams in RTMPS protocol to the CDN only when you enable transcoding.</li>
       </ul>
   </note>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters"><title>Parameter</title>
   <parml>
       <plentry id="url">
  <pt>url</pt>
  <pd>CDN 推流地址，格式为 RTMP 或 RTMPS。 The maximum length of this parameter is 1024 bytes. The URL address must not contain special characters, such as Chinese language characters.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>transcodingEnabled</pt>
  <pd>
      <p id="transcoding-desc">Whether to enable transcoding. <xref keyref="term-transocding"/> in a CDN live streaming converts the audio and video streams before pushing them to the CDN server. It applies to scenarios where a channel has multiple broadcasters and composite layout is needed<ul>
                                <li><ph keyref="true"/>: Enable transcoding.</li>
                                <li><ph keyref="false"/>: Disable transcoding.</li>
                            </ul></p>
      <note type="attention">If you set this parameter as <ph keyref="true"/>, ensure that you call the <xref keyref="setLiveTranscoding"/> method before this method.</note>
  </pd>
       </plentry>
   </parml>
        </section>
        <section id="return_values">
   <title>Returns</title>
   <ul>
       <li>0: Success.</li>
       <li>&lt; 0: Failure.<ul>
                        <li><codeph>ERR_INVALID_ARGUMENT</codeph>(-2): Invalid argument, usually because the URL address is null or the string length is 0.</li>
                        <li><codeph>ERR_NOT_INITIALIZED</codeph>(-7): You have not initialized the RTC engine when publishing the stream.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
   </ul>
        </section></refbody>
</reference>
