<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="class_livetranscoding">
    <title><ph keyref="LiveTranscoding"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc">This class manages the configurations of pushing streams to the CDN.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="prototype">
   <p conref="../conref/conref_rtc_api.dita#apidef/LiveTranscoding"/>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters">
   <title><text conref = "../conref/conref_api_metadata.dita#metadata/property"/></title>
   <parml>
   <plentry>
   <pt>width</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>The width of the video in pixels. The default value is 360.</p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>When pushing video streams to the CDN, ensure that <codeph>width</codeph> is at least 64; otherwise, the Agora server adjusts the value to 64.</li>
                            <li>When pushing audio streams to the CDN, set <codeph>width</codeph> and <codeph>height</codeph> as 0.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>height</pt>
  <pd>
      <p>The height of the video in pixels. The default value is 640.</p>
      <ul>
 <li>When pushing video streams to the CDN, ensure that <codeph>height</codeph> is at least 64; otherwise, the Agora server adjusts the value to 64.</li>
 <li>When pushing audio streams to the CDN, set <codeph>width</codeph> and <codeph>height</codeph> as 0.</li>
      </ul>
  </pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>videoBitrate</pt>
  <pd>Bitrate of the CDN live output video stream. The minimum encoding bitrate (Kbps). The default value is 400 Kbps. Set this parameter according to the Video Bitrate Table. If you set a bitrate beyond the proper range, the SDK automatically adapts it to a value within the range.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>videoFrameRate</pt>
  <pd>The video frame rate (fps) of the CDN live stream. The value range is (0,30], and the default value is 15.<note outputclass="note">The Agora server adjusts any value over 30 to 30.</note></pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>lowLatency</pt>
  <pd>
      <dl outputclass="deprecated">
 <dlentry>
     <dt>Deprecated</dt>
     <dd>This attribute is obsolete since v2.8.0, and Agora does not recommend it.</dd>
 </dlentry>
      </dl>
      <ul>
 <li>true: Low latency with unassured quality.</li>
 <li>false: (Default) High latency with assured quality.</li>
      </ul>
  </pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>videoGop</pt>
  <pd>The GOP (in frames) of the output video stream. 单位为帧。 The default value is 30.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
       <pt>videoCodecProfile</pt>
       <pd>
  <p>The encoding specifications of the output audio stream. See <xref keyref="VIDEO_CODEC_PROFILE_TYPE"/>.</p>
  <note outputclass="note">If you set this parameter to other values, Agora adjusts it to the default value 100.</note>
       </pd>
   </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>backgroundColor</pt>
  <pd>The background color of the output video in RGB hex value. Do not include # in the value. For example, use <codeph>0xFFB6C1</codeph> for light pink. The default value is <codeph>0x000000</codeph>(black).</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>userCount</pt>
  <pd>The number of users involved in transcoding.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>transcodingUsers</pt>
  <pd>
      <p>The transcoding configuration for each user (the maximum is 17 users). See . See <xref keyref="TranscodingUser"/>.</p>
  </pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>transcodingExtraInfo</pt>
  <pd>Reserved parameter: User-defined information to be sent to the CDN client receiving the pushed stream. This information is used to fill in the SEI frame of H.264/H.265 videos. The maximum length is 4096 bytes. For detailed information about SEI, see <xref href="https://docs.agora.io/cn/faq/sei" scope="external" format="html">SEI frame related issues</xref>.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>metadata</pt>
  <pd>
      <dl>
 <dlentry>
     <dt>Deprecated:</dt>
     <dd>This attribute is deprecated.</dd>
 </dlentry>
      </dl>The metadata sent to the CDN client.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>watermark</pt>
  <pd>The watermark image added to the output video. Only the PNG format is supported. After adding a watermark image, all of the CDN audience can see the image. For details, see <xref keyref="RtcImage"/>.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>backgroundImage</pt>
  <pd>The background image added to the output video. After adding a background image, all of the CDN audience can see the image. For details, see <xref keyref="RtcImage"/>.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>audioSampleRate</pt>
  <pd>The audio sampling rate (Hz) of the output stream. See <xref keyref="AUDIO_SAMPLE_RATE_TYPE"/>.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>audioBitrate</pt>
  <pd>The bitrate (Kbps) of the output video stream. A positive integer. The default value is 48, and the highest value is 128.</pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>audioChannels</pt>
  <pd>The number of audio channels for the CDN live stream. Agora recommends choosing 1 (mono), or 2 (stereo) audio channels. Special players are required if you choose option 3, 4, or<ul>
      <li>1: (Default) Mono</li>
      <li>2: Stereo.</li>
      <li>3: Three audio channels</li>
      <li>4: Four audio channels</li>
      <li>5: Five audio channels</li>
      </ul>
  </pd>
       </plentry>
       <plentry>
  <pt>audioCodecProfile</pt>
  <pd>The encoding specifications of the output audio stream. See <xref keyref="AUDIO_CODEC_PROFILE_TYPE"/>.</pd>
       </plentry>
   </parml>
        </section></refbody>
</reference>
