<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="class_transcodinguser">
    <title><ph keyref="TranscodingUser"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc">参与转码合流的每个主播的设置。</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="prototype">
   <p conref="../conref/conref_rtc_api.dita#apidef/TranscodingUser"/>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters">
   <title>Attributes</title>
        <parml>
   <plentry>
       <pt>uid</pt>
       <pd>
  <p>User ID of the user displaying the video in the CDN live.</p>
       </pd>
   </plentry>
   <plentry>
       <pt>x</pt>
       <pd>
  <p>The x coordinate (pixel) of the image on the video frame (taking the upper left corner of the video frame as the origin). 取值范围为[0, width]，width 为 <xref keyref="LiveTranscoding"/> 中设置的 <codeph>width</codeph>。</p></pd>
   </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt>y</pt>
                    <pd>The y coordinate (pixel) of the image on the video frame (taking the upper left corner of the video frame as the origin). 取值范围为[0, height]，height 为 <xref keyref="LiveTranscoding"/> 中设置的 <codeph>height</codeph>。</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt>width</pt>
                    <pd>The width (pixel) of the image on the video frame.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt>height</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>The height of the screen (pixel).</p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt>zOrder</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>The layer number of the screen. The value ranges from 0 to 100.<ul>
                                <li>0: (default) the video screen is at the bottom of the layer.</li>
                                <li>100: Top layer.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                        <note type="attention">
                            <ul>
                                <li>If zOrder is beyond this range, the SDK reports #<codeph>ERR_INVALID_ARGUMENT</codeph>.</li>
                                <li>As of v2.3, the SDK supports zOrder = 0.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt>alpha</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>(Optional) The transparency of the image. The value ranges between 0.0 and 100.0 .<ul>
                                <li>- 0.0: Completely transparent.</li>
                                <li>- 1.0: Opaque.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
            <plentry>
                <pt>audioChannel</pt>
                <pd>
                        <p>The audio channel where the host&apos;s audio is located. The number of destination channels. The default value is 0, and the value range is from 0 to 4.<ul id="ul_ugm_rrh_v4b">
                                <li><codeph></codeph>(Default) Supports dual channels at most, depending on the upstream of the host.</li>
                                <li><codeph></codeph>The host&apos;s audio uses the FL audio channel. If the host&apos;s upstream uses multiple audio channels, these channels are mixed into mono first.</li>
                                <li><codeph></codeph>The host&apos;s audio uses the FC audio channel. If the host&apos;s upstream uses multiple audio channels, these channels are mixed into mono first.</li>
                                <li><codeph></codeph>The host&apos;s audio uses the FR audio channel. If the host&apos;s upstream uses multiple audio channels, these channels are mixed into mono first.</li>
                                <li><codeph></codeph>The host&apos;s audio uses the BL audio channel. If the host&apos;s upstream uses multiple audio channels, these channels are mixed into mono first.</li>
                                <li><codeph></codeph>The host&apos;s audio uses the BR audio channel. If the host&apos;s upstream uses multiple audio channels, these channels are mixed into mono first.</li>
                                <li>`<codeph>0xFF</codeph>` or a value greater than `5`<codeph></codeph>: The host&apos;s audio is muted. The Agora server removes the host&apos;s audio.</li>
                            </ul>
                            <note type="attention">@note If the value is not `<codeph>0</codeph>`, a special player is required.</note></p>
                    </pd>
            </plentry>
        </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
