<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="product-intro">
    <title>Product Overview Introduction</title>
    <body>
        <p id="function">
            <table>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="col3"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Function</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                            <entry>Scenario</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row props="live">
                            <entry>Co-hosting in a channel</entry>
                            <entry>An audience switches to a co-host and interacts with the existing host.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       Large-scale live streams where hosts can invite the audience to interact with them.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Online games such as Murder Mystery and Werewolf Killing.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="lives">
                            <entry>Single Host</entry>
                            <entry>Low-latency live streaming by one host. The audience can join the channel and watch the live streaming.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul id="ul_skp_1fp_lrb">
                                    <li>
                                       Lecture Hall
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Showroom
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Live-stream Shopping
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Live match streaming
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Trivia Game
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                                <p>
                                   For the specific description of the scenarios above, see the note under the table.
                                </p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="lives">
                            <entry>Becoming a host</entry>
                            <entry>An audience member can switch their user role and become a host. Then they can interact with other hosts via audio and video.</entry>
                            <entry>-</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives">
                            <entry>Co-hosting across channels</entry>
                            <entry>Hosts interact with each other across channels.</entry>
                            <entry>PK Hosting.</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Audio mixing</entry>
                            <entry>Sends the local and online audio with the user's voice to other audience members in the channel.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       Online KTV.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Interactive music classes for children.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives video">
                            <entry>Screen sharing</entry>
                            <entry>Hosts share their screens with the audience in the channel. Supports specifying which screen or which window to share, and supports specifying the sharing region.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       Interactive online classes.
                                    </li>
                                    <li props="live">
                                       Live streaming of gaming hosts.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives video">
                            <entry>Basic image enhancement</entry>
                            <entry>Sets basic beauty effects, including skin smoothening, whitening, and cheek blushing.</entry>
                            <entry>Image enhancement in a video call.</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Modify the raw data</entry>
                            <entry>Developers obtain and modify the raw voice or video data of the SDK engine to create special effects, such as a voice change.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       To change the voice in an online voice chatroom.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Image enhancement in a live stream.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives video">
                            <entry>Customize the video source and renderer</entry>
                            <entry>Users process videos (from self-built cameras, screen sharing, or files) for image enhancement and filtering.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       To use a customized image enhancement library or pre-processing library.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       To customize the application's built-in image and video modules.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       To use other video sources, such as a recorded video.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       To provide flexible device management for exclusive video capture devices to avoid conflicts with other services.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives">
                            <entry>Push streams to the CDN</entry>
                               <entry>Sends the audio and video of your channel to other RTMP servers through the CDN:
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       Starts or stops publishing at any time.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Adds or removes an address while continuously publishing the stream.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Adjusts the picture-in-picture layout.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       To send a live stream to WeChat or Weibo.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       To allow more people to watch the live stream when the number of audience members in the channel reached the limit.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="audio">
                            <entry>Play the sound effect files</entry>
                            <entry>Enables developers to play specific sound effect files, adjust the volume, and set the playback position of the sound effect files.</entry>
                            <entry>Online chess or card games.</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="audio">
                            <entry>Voice changer and reverberation</entry>
                            <entry>Provides multiple presets to easily change the voice and set reverberation effects, also supports adjusting the pitch and using the equalization and reverberation modes flexibly.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       Online KTV.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       To change the voice in an online chatroom.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="audio">
                            <entry>Spatial sound effects</entry>
                            <entry>Sets the spatial sound effects for remote users to provide immersive experiences.</entry>
                            <entry>FPS games.</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="audio">
                            <entry>Enable two-channel/high-quality sound mode</entry>
                            <entry>Enables the two-channel and the high-quality sound mode.</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       Online music classes.
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       FM applications.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <note props="lives">
                <ul>
                    <li>
                       <b>Lecture Hall</b>: In a large online class, the low latency of Interactive Live Streaming Standard allows the teacher's audio and video to be quickly synchronized to the clients of thousands of students. The low latency between the audio and video of the teacher and the courseware makes real-time teaching more effective. Students can interact with the teacher through text messages, online
                       quizzes, and similar means to enhance the learning experience.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                       <b>Showroom</b>: In a showroom live streaming, the audience can send virtual gifts to the host. Thanks to the low latency of Interactive Live Streaming Standard, the host can promptly thank the audience for their gifts, and the audience can receive the host's thanks in a timely fashion, which helps to strengthen the emotional connection on both sides.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                       <b>Live-stream Shopping</b>: In a live-stream shopping scenario, customers can ask sellers for product and activity information via real-time messages. The low latency of Interactive Live Streaming Standard allows sellers to quickly respond to customers' questions, and customers can promptly see sellers' answers, thus encouraging transactions. In addition, the high synchronization of Interactive
                       Live Streaming Standard ensures a consistent experience on the audiences' clients for activities such as responding to flash sales, and grabbing time-sensitive offers (seckilling) and coupons.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                       <b>Live match streaming</b>: Live streaming sporting events or games in real time, synchronized so that there are no problematic delays.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                       <b>Trivia Game</b>: Apart from providing a smooth live streaming experience, the high synchronization of <ph keyref="product-name"/> also ensures that players receive the questions at the same time. This gives the audience members the same amount of time to answer—and an equal chance to win.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </note>
        </p>
        <p id="key-property">
            <table>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Property</entry>
                               <entry><ph keyref="product-name"/> specifications
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>SDK package size</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p props="video live lives">
                                   4.61 MB to 13.94 MB
                                </p>
                                <p props="audio">
                                   3.14 MB to 11.28 MB
                                </p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives video">
                            <entry>
                                <p props="live lives">
                                   Host capacity
                                </p>
                                <p props="video">
                                   Capacity
                                </p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>17 users</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives">
                            <entry>Audience capacity</entry>
                            <entry>1 million users </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live lives video">
                            <entry>Video profile</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       SDK video source: Up to 1080p @ 60 fps
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Custom video source: Up to 4K resolution
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Audio profile</entry>
                            <entry>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                       Sample rate: 16 kHz to 48 kHz
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                       Support for mono and stereo sound
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Audio anti-packet-loss rate</entry>
                            <entry>80% (uplink and downlink)</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live">
                            <entry>Latency on the audience's client</entry>
                            <entry>400 ms to 800 ms</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row props="live">
                            <entry>Latency between the host and the co-host</entry>
                            <entry>200 ms to 600 ms</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </p>
        <p id="compatability0">
            <ph keyref="product-name"/>支持 iOS、Android、Windows、macOS、Electron、Unity、Web、小程序，并支持平台间互通，具体的兼容性要求见下表。
        </p>
        <p id="compatability1">
           The platform compatibility of <ph keyref="product-name"/> is as follows:
            <ul>
                <li>
                   For the host's client, <ph keyref="product-name"/> supports platforms including Android, iOS, macOS, Windows, Web, and cross-platform frameworks (Unity, Electron, React Native, and Flutter).
                </li>
                <li>
                   For the audience's client, <ph keyref="product-name"/> supports platforms including Android, iOS, macOS, Windows, and Web.
                </li>
            </ul>
        </p>
    </body>
</topic>
