<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="api_ilocalspatialaudioengine_setplayerattenuation_ilocalspatialaudioengine">
    <title><ph keyref="setPlayerAttenuation_ILocalSpatialAudioEngine"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="cpp">Sets the audio attenuation properties for the media player.</ph></shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
                <indexterm keyref="setPlayerAttenuation_ILocalSpatialAudioEngine"/>
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <refbody>
        <section id="prototype">
            <p outputclass="codeblock">
                <codeblock props="cpp" outputclass="language-cpp">virtual int setPlayerAttenuation(int playerId, double attenuation, bool forceSet) = 0;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="detailed_desc" deliveryTarget="details" otherprops="no-title"/>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="cpp">
            <title>Parameters</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>playerId</pt>
                    <pd>ID of the media player. You can get the device ID by calling <xref keyref="getMediaPlayerId"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>attenuation</pt>
                    <pd>Audio attenuation coefficient for the remote user or media player, value range: [0, 1]. Value descriptions:
                        <ul>
                            <li>0: Broadcast mode. Volume and timbre do not attenuate with distance. The local user hears consistent volume and timbre regardless of distance.</li>
                            <li>(0, 0.5): Weak attenuation mode. Volume and timbre attenuate slightly during propagation. Sound travels farther than in real environments.</li>
                            <li>0.5: (Default) Simulates real-world audio attenuation. Equivalent to not setting the <codeph>speaker_attenuation</codeph> parameter.</li>
                            <li>(0.5, 1]: Strong attenuation mode. Volume and timbre attenuate rapidly during propagation.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>forceSet</pt>
                    <pd>Whether to forcibly apply the audio attenuation effect for the media player:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="true"/>: Force the use of <codeph>attenuation</codeph> to set the media player's attenuation. The <codeph>audioAttenuation</codeph> setting in <xref keyref="SpatialAudioZone"/> will not apply to the media player.</li>
                            <li><xref keyref="false"/>: Do not forcibly use <codeph>attenuation</codeph> to set the media player's audio attenuation. Details are as follows:
                                <ul>
                                    <li>If the sound source and listener are inside and outside the zone respectively, attenuation is determined by the <codeph>audioAttenuation</codeph> in <xref keyref="SpatialAudioZone"/>.</li>
                                    <li>If the sound source and listener are in the same zone or both outside, attenuation is determined by the <codeph>attenuation</codeph> in this method.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
        <section id="return_values" props="cpp">
            <title>Return Values</title>
            <p props="cpp">
                <ul>
                    <li>0: Success.</li>
                    <li>&lt; 0: Failure.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>