<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="class_screencaptureparameters">
    <title><ph keyref="ScreenCaptureParameters"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="cpp">Used to configure screen sharing parameters.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="prototype">
            <p outputclass="codeblock">
                <codeblock props="cpp" outputclass="language-cpp">struct ScreenCaptureParameters {
  VideoDimensions dimensions;
  int frameRate;
  int bitrate;
  bool captureMouseCursor;
  bool windowFocus;
  view_t* excludeWindowList;
  int excludeWindowCount;
  int highLightWidth;
  unsigned int highLightColor;
  bool enableHighLight;
};</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="cpp">
            <title>Properties</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>dimensions</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>When setting encoding resolution for document sharing scenarios, refer to the recommended settings.</note><ph>Encoded resolution of the screen sharing video stream. Default is 1920 × 1080, i.e., 2,073,600 pixels. Agora calculates fees based on this value. If the screen size differs from this value, the SDK adopts the following encoding strategy. Assuming <codeph>dimensions</codeph> is set to 1920 × 1080:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li>If the screen size is smaller, e.g., 1000 × 1000 pixels, the SDK encodes using the screen size (i.e., 1000 × 1000).</li>
                            <li>If the screen size is larger, e.g., 2000 × 1500 pixels, the SDK encodes with a maximum size not exceeding <codeph>dimensions</codeph> while maintaining the aspect ratio (4:3), i.e., 1440 × 1080.</li>
                        </ul><ph>See <xref keyref="VideoDimensions"/>.</ph></pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>frameRate</pt>
                    <pd>On Windows and macOS, indicates the encoding frame rate (fps) of the screen sharing video stream. Default is 5. Agora does not recommend setting values above 15.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>bitrate</pt>
                    <pd>On Windows and macOS, indicates the encoding bitrate (Kbps) of the screen sharing video stream. Default is 0, meaning the SDK automatically calculates the bitrate based on screen resolution.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>captureMouseCursor</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Due to macOS system limitations, setting this to <xref keyref="false"/> during screen sharing is ineffective (not affected when sharing a window).</note><ph>Whether to capture the mouse during screen sharing:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="true"/>: (default) Capture the mouse.</li>
                            <li><xref keyref="false"/>: Do not capture the mouse.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>windowFocus</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Due to macOS system limitations, if the app has multiple windows, only the main window will be brought to the foreground.</note><ph>When calling <xref keyref="startScreenCaptureByWindowId"/> to share a window, whether to bring the window to the foreground:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="true"/>: Bring to foreground.</li>
                            <li><xref keyref="false"/>: (default) Do not bring to foreground.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>excludeWindowList</pt>
                    <pd>List of window IDs to exclude. When starting screen sharing using <xref keyref="startScreenCaptureByDisplayId"/>, use this parameter to exclude specific windows. You can also use it to dynamically exclude windows via <xref keyref="updateScreenCaptureParameters"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>excludeWindowCount</pt>
                    <pd>Number of windows to exclude.
                        <note>On Windows, the maximum value is 24; exceeding this will cause exclusion to fail.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>highLightWidth</pt>
                    <pd>(macOS and Windows only) Width of the border (pixels). Default is 5, range is (0, 50].
                        <note>This parameter takes effect only when <codeph>highLighted</codeph> is set to <xref keyref="true"/>.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>highLightColor</pt>
                    <pd>(macOS and Windows only)
                        <ul>
                            <li>On Windows, the border color is in ARGB format. Default is 0xFF8CBF26.</li>
                            <li>On macOS, <codeph>COLOR_CLASS</codeph> represents <codeph>NSColor</codeph>.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>enableHighLight</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>When sharing part of a window or screen, if this is set to <xref keyref="true"/>, the SDK displays a border around the entire window or screen.</note><ph>(macOS and Windows only) Whether to display a border around the shared window or screen:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="true"/>: Display border.</li>
                            <li><xref keyref="false"/>: (default) Do not display border.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>