<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="class_screencaptureparameters">
    <title><ph keyref="ScreenCaptureParameters"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="cpp">Parameters used to configure screen sharing.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="prototype">
            <p outputclass="codeblock">
                <codeblock props="cpp" outputclass="language-cpp">struct ScreenCaptureParameters {
  bool captureAudio;
  ScreenAudioParameters audioParams;
  VideoDimensions dimensions;
  int frameRate;
  int bitrate;
  bool captureMouseCursor;
  bool windowFocus;
  view_t* excludeWindowList;
  int excludeWindowCount;
  int highLightWidth;
  unsigned int highLightColor;
  bool enableHighLight;
};</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="cpp">
            <title>Properties</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>dimensions</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>When setting the encoding resolution in document sharing scenarios, refer to the recommended settings.</note><ph>The encoding resolution of the screen sharing video stream. The default value is 1920 × 1080, which equals 2,073,600 pixels. Agora calculates the cost based on this value. If the screen size differs from this value, the SDK uses the following encoding strategy. Assuming <codeph>dimensions</codeph> is set to 1920 × 1080:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li>If the screen size is smaller than <codeph>dimensions</codeph>, such as 1000 × 1000 pixels, the SDK encodes using the screen size (i.e., 1000 × 1000 pixels).</li>
                            <li>If the screen size is larger than <codeph>dimensions</codeph>, such as 2000 × 1500 pixels, the SDK encodes using the maximum value that does not exceed <codeph>dimensions</codeph> while maintaining the screen's aspect ratio (4:3), i.e., 1440 × 1080.</li>
                        </ul><ph>See also <xref keyref="VideoDimensions"/>.</ph></pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>frameRate</pt>
                    <pd>On Windows and macOS, specifies the encoding frame rate (fps) of the screen sharing video stream. The default value is 5. Agora does not recommend setting a value greater than 15.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>bitrate</pt>
                    <pd>On Windows and macOS, specifies the encoding bitrate (Kbps) of the screen sharing video stream. The default value is 0, meaning the SDK automatically calculates the bitrate based on the current screen resolution.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>captureMouseCursor</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Due to macOS system limitations, setting this to <xref keyref="false"/> during screen sharing has no effect (not applicable when sharing a window).</note><ph>Whether to capture the mouse cursor during screen sharing:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="true"/>: (default) Capture the mouse.</li>
                            <li><xref keyref="false"/>: Do not capture the mouse.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>windowFocus</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Due to macOS system limitations, when setting this parameter to bring the window to the front, only the main window will be brought to the front if the current app has multiple windows.</note><ph>When calling the <xref keyref="startScreenCaptureByWindowId"/> method to share a window, whether to bring the window to the front:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="true"/>: Bring the window to the front.</li>
                            <li><xref keyref="false"/>: (default) Do not bring the window to the front.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>excludeWindowList</pt>
                    <pd>List of window IDs to exclude. When calling <xref keyref="startScreenCaptureByDisplayId"/> to start screen sharing, you can use this parameter to exclude specific windows. When calling <xref keyref="updateScreenCaptureParameters"/> to update screen sharing configuration, you can also use this parameter to dynamically exclude specific windows.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>excludeWindowCount</pt>
                    <pd>Number of windows to exclude.
                        <note>On Windows, the maximum value of this parameter is 24; exceeding this value will cause window exclusion to fail.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>highLightWidth</pt>
                    <pd>(Applicable only to macOS and Windows) Border width (in pixels). The default value is 5. Value range is (0, 50].
                        <note>This parameter takes effect only when <codeph>highLighted</codeph> is set to <xref keyref="true"/>.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>highLightColor</pt>
                    <pd>(Applicable only to macOS and Windows)
                        <ul>
                            <li>On Windows, the border color is in ARGB format. Default value is 0xFF8CBF26.</li>
                            <li>On macOS, <codeph>COLOR_CLASS</codeph> refers to <codeph>NSColor</codeph>.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>enableHighLight</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>When sharing a portion of a window or screen, if this parameter is set to <xref keyref="true"/>, the SDK displays a border around the entire window or screen.</note><ph>(Applicable only to macOS and Windows) Whether to show a border around the shared window or screen:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="true"/>: Show the border.</li>
                            <li><xref keyref="false"/>: (default) Do not show the border.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>