<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="enum_renewtokenerrorcode">
    <title><ph keyref="RENEW_TOKEN_ERROR_CODE"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="cpp">Error codes after calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="android">Error codes after calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="detailed_desc" deliveryTarget="details" otherprops="no-title" props="android cpp">
            <dl outputclass="since">
                <dlentry props="cpp">
                    <dt>Since</dt>
                    <dd>Added since version 4.6.0.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry props="android">
                    <dt>Since</dt>
                    <dd>Added since v4.6.0.</dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="android cpp">
            <title>Enumerations</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_SUCCESS</pt>
                    <pd>(0): Token updated successfully.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_FAILURE</pt>
                    <pd>(1): Token update failed due to unknown server error. Check the parameters used to generate the token, regenerate it, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_TOKEN_EXPIRED</pt>
                    <pd>(2): Token update failed because the provided token has expired. Generate a new token with a longer expiration time and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INVALID_TOKEN</pt>
                    <pd>(3): Token update failed because the provided token is invalid. Common causes include: App certificate is enabled in Agora Console but token is not used when joining the channel; <codeph>uid</codeph> in <codeph>joinChannel</codeph> is different from the one used to generate the token; channel name in <codeph>joinChannel</codeph> is different from the one used to generate the token. Check the token generation process, regenerate the token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INVALID_CHANNEL_NAME</pt>
                    <pd>(4): Token update failed because the channel name in the token does not match the current channel. Check the channel name, regenerate the token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INCONSISTENT_APPID</pt>
                    <pd>(5): Token update failed because the App ID in the token does not match the current App ID. Check the App ID, regenerate the token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_CANCELED_BY_NEW_REQUEST</pt>
                    <pd>(6): The previous token update request was canceled due to a new request.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="android">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_SUCCESS</pt>
                    <pd>(0): Token updated successfully.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="android">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_FAILURE</pt>
                    <pd>(1): Token update failed. It is recommended to generate a new token and retry calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="android">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_TOKEN_EXPIRED</pt>
                    <pd>(2): Token update failed because the provided token has expired. It is recommended to generate a token with a longer expiration time and retry calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="android">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INVALID_TOKEN</pt>
                    <pd>(3): Token update failed because the provided token is invalid. Common reasons include: the project enabled App Certificate in the Agora Console but did not use a token to join the channel; the <codeph>uid</codeph> specified in <codeph>joinChannel</codeph> is different from the one used to generate the token; the channel name specified in <codeph>joinChannel</codeph> is different from the one used to generate the token. It is recommended to check the token generation process, generate a new token, and retry calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="android">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INVALID_CHANNEL_NAME</pt>
                    <pd>(4): Token update failed because the channel name in the token does not match the current channel. It is recommended to check the channel name, generate a new token, and retry calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="android">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INCONSISTENT_APPID</pt>
                    <pd>(5): Token update failed because the App ID in the token does not match the current App ID. It is recommended to check the App ID, generate a new token, and retry calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="android">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_CANCELED_BY_NEW_REQUEST</pt>
                    <pd>(6): Token update was canceled because a new request was initiated, and the previous one was canceled.</pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>