<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="enum_localvideostreamreason">
    <title><ph keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="cpp">The reason for local video state change.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="cpp">
            <title>Enumerations</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_OK</pt>
                    <pd>(0): Local video is working properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_FAILURE</pt>
                    <pd>(1): An unspecified error occurred in the local video.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_NO_PERMISSION</pt>
                    <pd>(2): No permission to use the local video capture device. Prompt the user to grant permission and rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_BUSY</pt>
                    <pd>(3): The local video capture device is occupied. Prompt the user to check whether the camera is being used by another app or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_CAPTURE_FAILURE</pt>
                    <pd>(4): Failed to capture local video. Prompt the user to check whether the video capture device is functioning properly, whether the camera is occupied by another app, or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_CODEC_NOT_SUPPORT</pt>
                    <pd>(5): Local video encoding failed.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_CAPTURE_INBACKGROUND</pt>
                    <pd>(6): (iOS only) The app is in the background. Prompt the user that video cannot be captured while the app is in the background.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_CAPTURE_MULTIPLE_FOREGROUND_APPS</pt>
                    <pd>(7): (iOS only) The app window is in Slide Over, Split View, or Picture-in-Picture mode, and the camera is occupied by another app. Prompt the user that in these modes, if the camera is occupied by another app, video cannot be captured properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_NOT_FOUND</pt>
                    <pd>(8): No local video capture device found. Prompt the user to check whether the camera is properly connected or functioning, and rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_DISCONNECTED</pt>
                    <pd>(9): (macOS and Windows only) The current video capture device was disconnected (e.g., unplugged).</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_INVALID_ID</pt>
                    <pd>(10): (macOS and Windows only) The SDK cannot find the video device in the device list. Check whether the video device ID is valid.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_INTERRUPT</pt>
                    <pd>(14): (Android only) Video capture was interrupted. Possible reasons include: the camera is occupied by another app; the app switched to the background. You can use a foreground service notification to inform the system to continue video capture even when the app is in the background.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_FATAL_ERROR</pt>
                    <pd>(15): (Android only) A fatal error occurred with the video capture device. Prompt the user to turn off and restart the camera. If the issue persists, check for hardware failure.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_DEVICE_SYSTEM_PRESSURE</pt>
                    <pd>(101): The video capture device is unavailable due to high system pressure.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_MINIMIZED</pt>
                    <pd>(11): (macOS and Windows only) The shared window is minimized when calling <xref keyref="startScreenCaptureByWindowId"/>. The SDK cannot share a minimized window. Prompt the user to restore the window.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_CLOSED</pt>
                    <pd>(12): (macOS and Windows only) The shared window is closed, or a fullscreen window exited fullscreen mode. After exiting fullscreen, remote users will not see the shared window. To avoid showing a black screen to remote users, it is recommended to stop screen sharing immediately. Common scenarios include: local user closes the shared window; local user starts fullscreen slideshow and shares the window, then exits fullscreen; local user watches fullscreen web video or document and shares the window, then exits fullscreen.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_OCCLUDED</pt>
                    <pd>(13): (Windows only) The shared window is occluded by another window, and the SDK blacks out the occluded area.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_NOT_SUPPORTED</pt>
                    <pd>(20): Local screen sharing of the window is not supported.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_FAILURE</pt>
                    <pd>(21): (Windows and Android only) No data is available in the captured window.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_NO_PERMISSION</pt>
                    <pd>(22): (Windows and macOS only) No screen sharing permission.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_AUTO_FALLBACK</pt>
                    <pd>(24): (Windows only) An error occurred during screen sharing (possibly due to failure to occlude windows), causing performance degradation, but the screen sharing itself is not affected.
                        <note>During screen sharing, if window occlusion fails due to driver issues, the SDK reports this event and automatically falls back to sharing the entire screen. If your use case requires occluding specific windows for privacy, we recommend listening for this event and implementing additional privacy protection mechanisms when triggered.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_HIDDEN</pt>
                    <pd>(25): (Windows only) The shared window is hidden and not visible on the current screen.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_RECOVER_FROM_HIDDEN</pt>
                    <pd>(26): (Windows only) The shared window has recovered from a hidden state.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_RECOVER_FROM_MINIMIZED</pt>
                    <pd>(27): (macOS and Windows only) The shared window has recovered from a minimized state.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_PAUSED</pt>
                    <pd>(28): (Windows only) Screen sharing is paused. Common scenarios include switching to a secure desktop such as UAC dialog or Winlogon desktop.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_RESUMED</pt>
                    <pd>(29): (Windows only) Screen sharing has resumed from a paused state.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_DISPLAY_DISCONNECTED</pt>
                    <pd>(30): (Windows and macOS only) The display used for screen sharing has been disconnected, and screen sharing is paused. Prompt the user to restart screen sharing.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_STOPPED_BY_USER</pt>
                    <pd>(31): (HarmonyOS only) Screen sharing was stopped by the user.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_INTERRUPTED_BY_OTHER</pt>
                    <pd>(32): (HarmonyOS only) Screen sharing was interrupted by another screen sharing session.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_STOPPED_BY_CALL</pt>
                    <pd>(33): (HarmonyOS only) Screen sharing was stopped due to a SIM call.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="cpp">
                    <pt>LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_REASON_SCREEN_CAPTURE_EXCLUDE_WINDOW_FAILED</pt>
                    <pd>(34): (Windows only) Failed to exclude some windows in the exclude list during screen sharing.</pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>