<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="api_imediaplayer_setaudiodualmonomode">
    <title><ph keyref="setAudioDualMonoMode"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="electron">Sets the channel mode of the current audio file.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="rn">Sets the channel mode for the current audio file.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="flutter">Sets the channel mode of the current audio file.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="unity">Sets the channel mode of the current audio file.</ph></shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
                <indexterm keyref="setAudioDualMonoMode"/>
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <refbody>
        <section id="prototype">
            <p outputclass="codeblock">
                <codeblock props="electron" outputclass="language-typescript">abstract setAudioDualMonoMode(mode: AudioDualMonoMode): number;</codeblock>
                <codeblock props="rn" outputclass="language-typescript">abstract setAudioDualMonoMode(mode: AudioDualMonoMode): number;</codeblock>
                <codeblock props="flutter" outputclass="language-dart">Future&lt;void&gt; setAudioDualMonoMode(AudioDualMonoMode mode);</codeblock>
                <codeblock props="unity" outputclass="language-csharp">public abstract int SetAudioDualMonoMode(AUDIO_DUAL_MONO_MODE mode);</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="detailed_desc" deliveryTarget="details" otherprops="no-title">
            <p props="electron">In stereo audio files, the left and right channels can store different audio data. Depending on your needs, you can set the channel mode to original, left channel, right channel, or mixed mode. For example, in a KTV scenario, the left channel of the audio file stores the accompaniment, and the right channel stores the original vocals. If you only want to hear the accompaniment, call this method to set the channel mode to left channel; if you want to hear both accompaniment and vocals, set the mode to mixed.</p>
            <p props="rn">In stereo audio files, the left and right channels can store different audio data. Depending on your needs, you can set the channel mode to original, left channel, right channel, or mixed mode. For example, in a KTV scenario, the left channel may store the accompaniment and the right channel the original vocals. If you only want to hear the accompaniment, call this method to set the channel mode to left channel; if you want to hear both, set it to mixed mode.</p>
            <p props="flutter">In stereo audio files, the left and right channels can store different audio data. Depending on your needs, you can set the channel mode to original, left channel, right channel, or mixed mode. For example, in a KTV scenario, the left channel of an audio file stores the accompaniment, and the right channel stores the original vocal. If you only want to hear the accompaniment, call this method to set the channel mode to left channel; if you want to hear both the accompaniment and the original vocal, set the channel mode to mixed mode.</p>
            <p props="unity">In stereo audio files, the left and right channels can store different audio data. Depending on your needs, you can set the channel mode to original, left, right, or mixed. For example, in a karaoke (KTV) scenario, the left channel of the audio file stores the accompaniment, while the right channel stores the original vocals. If you only want to hear the accompaniment, call this method to set the channel mode to left. If you want to hear both the accompaniment and the original vocals, set the channel mode to mixed.</p>
            <note props="electron">
                <ul>
                    <li>You need to call this method after calling <xref keyref="open"/>.</li>
                    <li>This method only applies to stereo audio files.</li>
                </ul>
            </note>
            <note props="rn">
                <ul>
                    <li>You need to call this method after calling <xref keyref="open"/>.</li>
                    <li>This method is applicable only to stereo audio files.</li>
                </ul>
            </note>
            <note props="flutter">
                <ul>
                    <li>You need to call this method after calling <xref keyref="open"/>.</li>
                    <li>This method applies to stereo audio files only.</li>
                </ul>
            </note>
            <note props="unity">
                <ul>
                    <li>You need to call this method after calling <xref keyref="open"/>.</li>
                    <li>This method is only applicable to stereo audio files.</li>
                </ul>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="electron flutter rn unity">
            <title>Parameters</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>mode</pt>
                    <pd>Channel mode. See <xref keyref="AUDIO_DUAL_MONO_MODE"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>mode</pt>
                    <pd>Channel mode. See <xref keyref="AUDIO_DUAL_MONO_MODE"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>mode</pt>
                    <pd>Channel mode. See <xref keyref="AUDIO_DUAL_MONO_MODE"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>mode</pt>
                    <pd>Channel mode. See <xref keyref="AUDIO_DUAL_MONO_MODE"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
        <section id="return_values" props="electron flutter rn unity">
            <title>Return Values</title>
            <p props="electron">
                <ul>
                    <li>0: Success.</li>
                    <li>&lt; 0: Failure. See [Error Codes](https://docs.agora.io/en/video-calling/troubleshooting/error-codes) for details and resolution suggestions.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p props="rn">
                <ul>
                    <li>0: Success.</li>
                    <li>&lt; 0: Failure. See [Error Code](https://doc.shengwang.cn/api-ref/rtc/rn/error-code) for details and resolution suggestions.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p props="flutter">When the method call succeeds, there is no return value; when fails, the <xref keyref="AgoraRtcException"/> exception is thrown. You need to catch the exception and handle it accordingly. See [Error Codes](https://docs.agora.io/en/video-calling/troubleshooting/error-codes) for details and resolution suggestions.</p>
            <p props="unity">
                <ul>
                    <li>0: Success.</li>
                    <li>&lt; 0: Failure. See [Error Codes](https://docs.agora.io/en/video-calling/troubleshooting/error-codes) for details and resolution suggestions.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>