<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="enum_renewtokenerrorcode">
    <title><ph keyref="RENEW_TOKEN_ERROR_CODE"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="electron">Error codes after calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="rn">Error codes after calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="flutter">Error codes after calling <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="unity">Error codes after calling <codeph>renewToken</codeph>.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="detailed_desc" deliveryTarget="details" otherprops="no-title" props="electron flutter rn unity">
            <dl outputclass="since">
                <dlentry props="electron">
                    <dt>Since</dt>
                    <dd>Available since 4.6.0.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry props="rn">
                    <dt>Since</dt>
                    <dd>Available since v4.6.0.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry props="flutter">
                    <dt>Since</dt>
                    <dd>Available since 4.6.0.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry props="unity">
                    <dt>Since</dt>
                    <dd>Available since 4.6.0.</dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="electron flutter rn unity">
            <title>Enumerations</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>RenewTokenSuccess</pt>
                    <pd>(0): Token updated successfully.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>RenewTokenFailure</pt>
                    <pd>(1): Token update failed due to an unknown server error. Check the parameters used to generate the Token, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>RenewTokenTokenExpired</pt>
                    <pd>(2): Token update failed because the provided Token has expired. Generate a new Token with a longer expiration time and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>RenewTokenInvalidToken</pt>
                    <pd>(3): Token update failed because the provided Token is invalid. Common causes include: App certificate is enabled in the Agora Console but Token is not used when joining the channel; the <codeph>uid</codeph> specified in <xref keyref="joinChannel2"/> does not match the one used to generate the Token; the channel name specified in <xref keyref="joinChannel2"/> does not match the one used to generate the Token. Check the Token generation process, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>RenewTokenInvalidChannelName</pt>
                    <pd>(4): Token update failed because the channel name in the Token does not match the current channel. Check the channel name, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>RenewTokenInconsistentAppid</pt>
                    <pd>(5): Token update failed because the App ID in the Token does not match the current App ID. Check the App ID, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>RenewTokenCanceledByNewRequest</pt>
                    <pd>(6): The previous Token update request is canceled due to a new request being initiated.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>RenewTokenSuccess</pt>
                    <pd>(0): Token updated successfully.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>RenewTokenFailure</pt>
                    <pd>(1): Token update failed due to an unknown server error. It is recommended to check the parameters used to generate the Token, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>RenewTokenTokenExpired</pt>
                    <pd>(2): Token update failed because the provided Token has expired. It is recommended to generate a new Token with a longer expiration time and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>RenewTokenInvalidToken</pt>
                    <pd>(3): Token update failed because the provided Token is invalid. Common causes include: the project has enabled App Certificate in the Agora Console but did not use a Token when joining the channel; the <codeph>uid</codeph> specified in <xref keyref="joinChannel2"/> does not match the one used to generate the Token; the channel name specified in <xref keyref="joinChannel2"/> does not match the one used to generate the Token. It is recommended to check the Token generation process, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>RenewTokenInvalidChannelName</pt>
                    <pd>(4): Token update failed because the channel name in the Token does not match the current channel. It is recommended to check the channel name, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>RenewTokenInconsistentAppid</pt>
                    <pd>(5): Token update failed because the App ID in the Token does not match the current App ID. It is recommended to check the App ID, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>RenewTokenCanceledByNewRequest</pt>
                    <pd>(6): The previous Token update request was canceled due to a new request being initiated.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>renewTokenSuccess</pt>
                    <pd>(0): Token updated successfully.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>renewTokenFailure</pt>
                    <pd>(1): Token update failed due to an unknown server error. Check the parameters used to generate the Token, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>renewTokenTokenExpired</pt>
                    <pd>(2): Token update failed because the provided Token has expired. Generate a new Token with a longer expiration time and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>renewTokenInvalidToken</pt>
                    <pd>(3): Token update failed because the provided Token is invalid. Common reasons include: the project has enabled App Certificate in the Agora Console but the Token was not used when joining the channel; the <codeph>uid</codeph> specified in <xref keyref="joinChannel2"/> is different from the one used to generate the Token; the channel name specified in <xref keyref="joinChannel2"/> is different from the one used to generate the Token. Check the Token generation process, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>renewTokenInvalidChannelName</pt>
                    <pd>(4): Token update failed because the channel name in the Token does not match the current channel. Check the channel name, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>renewTokenInconsistentAppid</pt>
                    <pd>(5): Token update failed because the App ID in the Token does not match the current App ID. Check the App ID, regenerate the Token, and retry <xref keyref="renewToken"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>renewTokenCanceledByNewRequest</pt>
                    <pd>(6): The previous Token update request was canceled due to a new request being initiated.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_SUCCESS</pt>
                    <pd>(0): Token updated successfully.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_FAILURE</pt>
                    <pd>(1): Token update failed due to an unknown server error. It is recommended to check the parameters used to generate the Token, regenerate the Token, and retry <codeph>renewToken</codeph>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_TOKEN_EXPIRED</pt>
                    <pd>(2): Token update failed because the provided Token has expired. It is recommended to generate a new Token with a longer expiration time and retry <codeph>renewToken</codeph>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INVALID_TOKEN</pt>
                    <pd>(3): Token update failed because the provided Token is invalid. Common causes include: the project has enabled App Certificate in the Agora Console but Token is not used when joining the channel; the <codeph>uid</codeph> specified in <codeph>joinChannel</codeph> is inconsistent with the one used to generate the Token; the channel name specified in <codeph>joinChannel</codeph> is inconsistent with the one used to generate the Token. It is recommended to check the Token generation process, regenerate the Token, and retry <codeph>renewToken</codeph>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INVALID_CHANNEL_NAME</pt>
                    <pd>(4): Token update failed because the channel name in the Token is inconsistent with the current channel. It is recommended to check the channel name, regenerate the Token, and retry <codeph>renewToken</codeph>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_INCONSISTENT_APPID</pt>
                    <pd>(5): Token update failed because the App ID in the Token is inconsistent with the current App ID. It is recommended to check the App ID, regenerate the Token, and retry <codeph>renewToken</codeph>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>RENEW_TOKEN_CANCELED_BY_NEW_REQUEST</pt>
                    <pd>(6): The previous Token update request was canceled due to a new request being initiated.</pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>