<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="enum_earmonitoringfiltertype">
    <title><ph keyref="EAR_MONITORING_FILTER_TYPE"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="electron">Ear monitoring audio filter type.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="rn">Ear monitoring audio filter type.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="flutter">Ear monitoring audio filter type.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="unity">Ear monitoring audio filter type.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="electron flutter rn unity">
            <title>Enumerations</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterNone</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;0: Do not add audio filters in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterBuiltInAudioFilters</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;1: Add vocal effect audio filters in ear monitoring. If you implement features such as voice beautifier or sound effects, users can hear the processed sound in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterNoiseSuppression</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;2: Add noise suppression audio filters in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterReusePostProcessingFilter</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;15: Reuse the audio filters already applied on the sending side. Reusing audio filters reduces CPU usage for ear monitoring but increases ear monitoring latency. Suitable for scenarios where low CPU usage is prioritized over latency.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterNone</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;0: Do not add audio filters in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterBuiltInAudioFilters</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;1: Add vocal effect audio filters in ear monitoring. If you implement features such as voice beautification or sound effects, users can hear the processed sound in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterNoiseSuppression</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;2: Add noise suppression audio filters in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>EarMonitoringFilterReusePostProcessingFilter</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;15: Reuse audio filters that have already been applied on the sending side. Reusing audio filters reduces CPU usage for ear monitoring, but increases latency. Suitable for scenarios where reducing CPU consumption is more important than minimizing ear monitoring latency.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>earMonitoringFilterNone</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;0: Do not add audio filter to ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>earMonitoringFilterBuiltInAudioFilters</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;1: Add vocal effect audio filter to ear monitoring. If you implement features like voice beautification or sound effects, users can hear the processed sound through ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>earMonitoringFilterNoiseSuppression</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;2: Add noise suppression audio filter to ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>earMonitoringFilterReusePostProcessingFilter</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;15: Reuse the audio filter already applied on the sending end. Reusing the audio filter reduces CPU usage for ear monitoring but increases ear monitoring latency. Suitable for scenarios where lower CPU usage is required and latency is not critical.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>EAR_MONITORING_FILTER_NONE</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;0: Do not add audio filters in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>EAR_MONITORING_FILTER_BUILT_IN_AUDIO_FILTERS</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;1: Add vocal effect audio filters in ear monitoring. If you implement features like voice beautification or sound effects, users can hear the processed sound in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>EAR_MONITORING_FILTER_NOISE_SUPPRESSION</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;2: Add noise suppression audio filters in ear monitoring.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>EAR_MONITORING_FILTER_REUSE_POST_PROCESSING_FILTER</pt>
                    <pd>1&lt;&lt;15: Reuse audio filters that have already been applied on the sending side. Reusing filters reduces CPU usage for ear monitoring but increases latency, suitable for scenarios where lower CPU usage is preferred and latency is not critical.</pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>