<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="enum_errorcodetype">
    <title><ph keyref="ERROR_CODE_TYPE"/></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc" props="electron">Error codes.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="rn">Error codes.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="flutter">Error codes.</ph><ph id="shortdesc" props="unity">Error codes.</ph></shortdesc>
    <refbody>
        <section id="detailed_desc" deliveryTarget="details" otherprops="no-title" props="electron flutter rn unity">
            <p props="electron">Error codes indicate that the SDK has encountered an unrecoverable error and requires intervention from the application. For example, an error is returned when the camera fails to open, and the app needs to prompt the user that the camera cannot be used.</p>
            <p props="rn">Error codes indicate that the SDK encountered an unrecoverable error and requires intervention from the application. For example, an error is returned when the camera fails to open, and the app needs to inform the user that the camera cannot be used.</p>
            <p props="flutter">Error codes indicate that the SDK has encountered an unrecoverable error requiring application intervention. For example, an error is returned when the camera fails to open, and the app needs to notify the user that the camera cannot be used.</p>
            <p props="unity">Error codes indicate that the SDK has encountered an unrecoverable error and requires intervention from the application. For example, an error is returned when the camera fails to open, and the app needs to notify the user that the camera cannot be used.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters" deliveryTarget="details" props="electron flutter rn unity">
            <title>Enumerations</title>
            <parml>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrOk</pt>
                    <pd>0: No error.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrFailed</pt>
                    <pd>1: A general error (no specific classification of the error cause). Please try calling the method again.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidArgument</pt>
                    <pd>2: An invalid parameter was set in the method. For example, the specified channel name contains illegal characters. Please reset the parameter.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrNotReady</pt>
                    <pd>3: The SDK is not ready. Possible reasons:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> failed to initialize. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>The user has not joined the channel when calling the method. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>The user has not left the channel when calling the <xref keyref="rate"/> or <xref keyref="complain"/> method. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>The audio module is not enabled.</li>
                            <li>The assembly is incomplete.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrNotSupported</pt>
                    <pd>4: The current state of <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> does not support this operation. Possible reasons:
                        <ul>
                            <li>When using built-in encryption, the encryption mode is incorrect, or loading the external encryption library failed. Please check whether the encryption enum value is correct or reload the external encryption library.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrRefused</pt>
                    <pd>5: This method call was rejected. Possible reasons:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> failed to initialize. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>The channel name was set to an empty string <codeph>""</codeph> when joining the channel. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                            <li>In multi-channel scenarios, the channel name already exists when calling <xref keyref="joinChannelEx"/> to join a channel. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrBufferTooSmall</pt>
                    <pd>6: The buffer size is insufficient to store the returned data.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrNotInitialized</pt>
                    <pd>7: The method was called before <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> was initialized. Please ensure that the <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> object is created and initialized before calling this method.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidState</pt>
                    <pd>8: The current state is invalid.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrNoPermission</pt>
                    <pd>9: No permission to operate. Please check whether the user has granted the app permission to use audio and video devices.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrTimedout</pt>
                    <pd>10: Method call timed out. Some method calls require a response from the SDK. If the SDK takes too long to process the event and does not return within 10 seconds, this error occurs.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrJoinChannelRejected</pt>
                    <pd>17: Joining the channel was rejected. Possible reasons:
                        <ul>
                            <li>The user is already in the channel. It is recommended to determine whether the user is in the channel via the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback. Do not call this method again to join the channel unless receiving the <codeph>ConnectionStateDisconnected</codeph>(1) state.</li>
                            <li>The user attempted to join the channel without calling <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> after initiating a call test with <xref keyref="startEchoTest3"/>. After starting a call test, you must call <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> to end the current test before joining the channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrLeaveChannelRejected</pt>
                    <pd>18: Failed to leave the channel. Possible reasons:
                        <ul>
                            <li>The user has already left the channel before calling <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/>. Stop calling this method.</li>
                            <li>The user called <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/> before joining the channel. No additional action is needed in this case.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAlreadyInUse</pt>
                    <pd>19: The resource is already in use and cannot be reused.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAborted</pt>
                    <pd>20: The SDK aborted the request, possibly due to too many requests.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInitNetEngine</pt>
                    <pd>21: On Windows, specific firewall settings caused <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> to fail initialization and crash.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrResourceLimited</pt>
                    <pd>22: The SDK failed to allocate resources, possibly because the app is using too many resources or system resources are exhausted.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidAppId</pt>
                    <pd>101: Invalid App ID. Please use a valid App ID to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidChannelName</pt>
                    <pd>102: Invalid channel name. Possible reason is an incorrect data type for the parameter. Please use a valid channel name to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrNoServerResources</pt>
                    <pd>103: Unable to obtain server resources in the current region. Try specifying another region when initializing <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrTokenExpired</pt>
                    <pd>109: The current Token has expired and is no longer valid. Please request a new Token from your server and call <xref keyref="renewToken"/> to update the Token.
                        <note>Deprecated: This enum is deprecated. Use the <codeph>ConnectionChangedTokenExpired</codeph>(9) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidToken</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Deprecated: This enum is deprecated. Use the <codeph>ConnectionChangedInvalidToken</codeph>(8) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note><ph>110: Invalid Token. Common reasons:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li>App certificate is enabled in the console, but App ID + Token authentication is not used. When the project has App certificate enabled, Token authentication must be used.</li>
                            <li>The <codeph>uid</codeph> field used when generating the Token does not match the <codeph>uid</codeph> used when joining the channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrConnectionInterrupted</pt>
                    <pd>111: Network connection interrupted. After the SDK establishes a connection with the server, it loses the network connection for more than 4 seconds.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrConnectionLost</pt>
                    <pd>112: Network connection lost. The network is disconnected and the SDK fails to reconnect to the server within 10 seconds.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrNotInChannel</pt>
                    <pd>113: The user is not in the channel when calling the <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/> method.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrSizeTooLarge</pt>
                    <pd>114: The data length exceeds 1 KB when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrBitrateLimit</pt>
                    <pd>115: The data sending frequency exceeds the limit (6 KB/s) when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrTooManyDataStreams</pt>
                    <pd>116: The number of data streams created exceeds the limit (5 streams) when calling <xref keyref="createDataStream2"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrStreamMessageTimeout</pt>
                    <pd>117: Data stream sending timed out.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrSetClientRoleNotAuthorized</pt>
                    <pd>119: Failed to switch user role. Please try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrDecryptionFailed</pt>
                    <pd>120: Media stream decryption failed. Possibly due to an incorrect key used when the user joined the channel. Please check the key entered when joining the channel or guide the user to try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidUserId</pt>
                    <pd>121: Invalid user ID.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrDatastreamDecryptionFailed</pt>
                    <pd>122: Data stream decryption failed. Possibly due to an incorrect key used when the user joined the channel. Please check the key entered when joining the channel or guide the user to try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrClientIsBannedByServer</pt>
                    <pd>123: The user is banned by the server.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrEncryptedStreamNotAllowedPublish</pt>
                    <pd>130: The SDK does not support pushing encrypted streams to the CDN.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidUserAccount</pt>
                    <pd>134: Invalid user account, possibly due to invalid parameters.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrPcmsendFormat</pt>
                    <pd>200: Unsupported PCM format.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrPcmsendBufferoverflow</pt>
                    <pd>201: Buffer overflow due to PCM sending rate being too fast.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrCertRaw</pt>
                    <pd>1001: Failed to load media engine.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAdmGeneralError</pt>
                    <pd>1005: Audio device error (unspecified). Please check whether the audio device is occupied by another application or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAdmInitPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1008: Failed to initialize playback device. Please check whether the playback device is occupied by another application or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStartPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1009: Failed to start playback device. Please check whether the playback device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStopPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1010: Failed to stop playback device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAdmInitRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1011: Failed to initialize recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStartRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1012: Failed to start recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStopRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1013: Failed to stop recording device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="electron">
                    <pt>ErrVdmCameraNotAuthorized</pt>
                    <pd>1501: No permission to use the camera. Please check whether camera permission is enabled.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrOk</pt>
                    <pd>0: No error.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrFailed</pt>
                    <pd>1: A general error (no specific classification). Please retry the method call.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidArgument</pt>
                    <pd>2: Invalid parameter set in the method. For example, the specified channel name contains illegal characters. Please reset the parameter.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrNotReady</pt>
                    <pd>3: The SDK is not ready. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization failed. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>The user has not joined a channel when calling the method. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>The user has not left the channel when calling <xref keyref="rate"/> or <xref keyref="complain"/>. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>The audio module is not enabled.</li>
                            <li>The assembly is incomplete.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrNotSupported</pt>
                    <pd>4: The current state of <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> does not support this operation. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>When using built-in encryption, the encryption mode is incorrect, or loading the external encryption library failed. Please check if the encryption enumeration value is correct, or reload the external encryption library.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrRefused</pt>
                    <pd>5: This method call was rejected. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization failed. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>The channel name was set to an empty string <codeph>""</codeph> when joining the channel. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                            <li>In multi-channel scenarios, the specified channel name already exists when calling <xref keyref="joinChannelEx"/> to join the channel. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrBufferTooSmall</pt>
                    <pd>6: The buffer size is insufficient to hold the returned data.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrNotInitialized</pt>
                    <pd>7: The method is called before <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> is initialized. Please ensure the <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> object is created and initialized before calling this method.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidState</pt>
                    <pd>8: The current state is invalid.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrNoPermission</pt>
                    <pd>9: No permission to operate. Please check whether the user has granted the app access to audio and video devices.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrTimedout</pt>
                    <pd>10: The method call timed out. Some method calls require the SDK to return a result. If the SDK takes too long (over 10 seconds) to process the event, this error occurs.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrJoinChannelRejected</pt>
                    <pd>17: Joining the channel was rejected. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>The user is already in the channel. It is recommended to determine whether the user is in the channel through the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback. Do not call this method again to join the channel unless receiving the <codeph>ConnectionStateDisconnected</codeph>(1) state.</li>
                            <li>The user attempted to join a channel after calling <xref keyref="startEchoTest3"/> for a call test without first calling <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> to end the current test. After starting a call test, you must call <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> to end the test before joining a channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrLeaveChannelRejected</pt>
                    <pd>18: Failed to leave the channel. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>The user has already left the channel before calling <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/>. Just stop calling this method.</li>
                            <li>The user called <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/> to exit the channel without having joined it. No further action is needed in this case.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAlreadyInUse</pt>
                    <pd>19: The resource is already in use and cannot be reused.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAborted</pt>
                    <pd>20: The SDK aborted the request, possibly due to too many requests.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInitNetEngine</pt>
                    <pd>21: Specific firewall settings on Windows caused <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization to fail and crash.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrResourceLimited</pt>
                    <pd>22: The SDK failed to allocate resources, possibly due to excessive resource usage by the app or system resource exhaustion.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidAppId</pt>
                    <pd>101: Invalid App ID. Please use a valid App ID to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidChannelName</pt>
                    <pd>102: Invalid channel name. Possible reason is incorrect data type for the parameter. Please use a valid channel name to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrNoServerResources</pt>
                    <pd>103: Unable to acquire server resources in the current region. Try specifying another region when initializing <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrTokenExpired</pt>
                    <pd>109: The current Token has expired and is no longer valid. Please request a new Token from your server and call <xref keyref="renewToken"/> to update it.
                        <note>Deprecated: This enumeration is deprecated. Use <codeph>ConnectionChangedTokenExpired</codeph>(9) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidToken</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Deprecated: This enumeration is deprecated. Use <codeph>ConnectionChangedInvalidToken</codeph>(8) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note><ph>110: Invalid Token. Common reasons include:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li>App certificate is enabled in the console, but App ID + Token authentication is not used. When the App certificate is enabled, Token authentication must be used.</li>
                            <li>The <codeph>uid</codeph> field used when generating the Token does not match the <codeph>uid</codeph> used when the user joins the channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrConnectionInterrupted</pt>
                    <pd>111: Network connection interrupted. After the SDK establishes a connection with the server, it loses network connectivity for more than 4 seconds.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrConnectionLost</pt>
                    <pd>112: Network connection lost. The network is disconnected and the SDK fails to reconnect to the server within 10 seconds.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrNotInChannel</pt>
                    <pd>113: The user is not in a channel when calling the <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/> method.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrSizeTooLarge</pt>
                    <pd>114: The data length exceeds 1 KB when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrBitrateLimit</pt>
                    <pd>115: The data sending rate exceeds the limit (6 KB/s) when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrTooManyDataStreams</pt>
                    <pd>116: The number of data streams created exceeds the limit (5) when calling <xref keyref="createDataStream2"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrStreamMessageTimeout</pt>
                    <pd>117: Data stream sending timed out.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrSetClientRoleNotAuthorized</pt>
                    <pd>119: Failed to switch user role. Please try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrDecryptionFailed</pt>
                    <pd>120: Media stream decryption failed. Possibly due to an incorrect key used when the user joined the channel. Please check the key entered when joining the channel, or guide the user to try rejoining.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidUserId</pt>
                    <pd>121: Invalid user ID.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrDatastreamDecryptionFailed</pt>
                    <pd>122: Data stream decryption failed. Possibly due to an incorrect key used when the user joined the channel. Please check the key entered when joining the channel, or guide the user to try rejoining.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrClientIsBannedByServer</pt>
                    <pd>123: This user is banned by the server.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrEncryptedStreamNotAllowedPublish</pt>
                    <pd>130: The SDK does not support pushing encrypted streams to CDN.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrInvalidUserAccount</pt>
                    <pd>134: Invalid user account, possibly due to an invalid parameter.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrPcmsendFormat</pt>
                    <pd>200: Unsupported PCM format.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrPcmsendBufferoverflow</pt>
                    <pd>201: Buffer overflow due to PCM sending rate being too fast.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrCertRaw</pt>
                    <pd>1001: Failed to load the media engine.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAdmGeneralError</pt>
                    <pd>1005: Audio device error (unspecified). Please check whether the audio device is occupied by another application, or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAdmInitPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1008: Failed to initialize the playback device. Please check whether the playback device is occupied by another application, or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStartPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1009: Failed to start the playback device. Please check whether the playback device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStopPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1010: Failed to stop the playback device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAdmInitRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1011: Failed to initialize the recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly, or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStartRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1012: Failed to start the recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrAdmStopRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1013: Failed to stop the recording device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="rn">
                    <pt>ErrVdmCameraNotAuthorized</pt>
                    <pd>1501: No permission to use the camera. Please check whether camera permission is enabled.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errOk</pt>
                    <pd>0: No error.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errFailed</pt>
                    <pd>1: General error (uncategorized error cause). Please try calling the method again.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInvalidArgument</pt>
                    <pd>2: Invalid parameter set in the method. For example, the specified channel name contains illegal characters. Please reset the parameters.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errNotReady</pt>
                    <pd>3: SDK is not ready. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization failed. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>User has not joined the channel when calling the method. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>User has not left the channel when calling <xref keyref="rate"/> or <xref keyref="complain"/>. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>Audio module is not enabled.</li>
                            <li>Incomplete assembly.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errNotSupported</pt>
                    <pd>4: The current state of <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> does not support this operation. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>When using built-in encryption, the encryption mode is incorrect or loading the external encryption library failed. Please check whether the encryption enum value is correct or reload the external encryption library.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errRefused</pt>
                    <pd>5: This method call was rejected. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization failed. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>An empty string <codeph>""</codeph> was set as the channel name when joining the channel. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                            <li>In multi-channel scenarios, the specified channel name already exists when calling <xref keyref="joinChannelEx"/> to join a channel. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errBufferTooSmall</pt>
                    <pd>6: Buffer size is insufficient to hold the returned data.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errNotInitialized</pt>
                    <pd>7: Method is called before <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> is initialized. Please ensure that the <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> object is created and initialized before calling this method.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInvalidState</pt>
                    <pd>8: Invalid current state.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errNoPermission</pt>
                    <pd>9: No permission to operate. Please check whether the user has granted the app permission to use audio and video devices.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errTimedout</pt>
                    <pd>10: Method call timed out. Some method calls require a result from the SDK. If the SDK takes too long to process the event and does not return within 10 seconds, this error occurs.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errJoinChannelRejected</pt>
                    <pd>17: Joining the channel was rejected. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>The user is already in the channel. It is recommended to determine whether the user is in the channel via the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback. Do not call this method again to join the channel unless receiving the <codeph>connectionStateDisconnected</codeph>(1) state.</li>
                            <li>After calling <xref keyref="startEchoTest3"/> for a call test, the user attempts to join the channel without calling <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> to end the current test. After starting the call test, you must call <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> to end the test before joining the channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errLeaveChannelRejected</pt>
                    <pd>18: Failed to leave the channel. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>The user has already left the channel before calling <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/>. Stop calling this method.</li>
                            <li>The user calls <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/> to exit the channel without having joined it. No further action is needed in this case.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAlreadyInUse</pt>
                    <pd>19: The resource is already in use and cannot be reused.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAborted</pt>
                    <pd>20: SDK aborted the request, possibly due to too many requests.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInitNetEngine</pt>
                    <pd>21: Specific firewall settings on Windows caused <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization to fail and crash.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errResourceLimited</pt>
                    <pd>22: SDK failed to allocate resources, possibly because the app is using too many resources or system resources are exhausted.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInvalidAppId</pt>
                    <pd>101: Invalid App ID. Please use a valid App ID to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInvalidChannelName</pt>
                    <pd>102: Invalid channel name. Possible reason is incorrect data type set for the parameter. Please use a valid channel name to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errNoServerResources</pt>
                    <pd>103: Unable to obtain server resources in the current region. Try specifying a different region when initializing <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errTokenExpired</pt>
                    <pd>109: The current Token has expired and is no longer valid. Please request a new Token from the server and call <xref keyref="renewToken"/> to update it.
                        <note>Deprecated: This enum is deprecated. Use <codeph>connectionChangedTokenExpired</codeph>(9) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInvalidToken</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Deprecated: This enum is deprecated. Use <codeph>connectionChangedInvalidToken</codeph>(8) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note><ph>110: Invalid Token. Common reasons include:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li>App certificate is enabled in the console, but App ID + Token authentication is not used. When the project enables the App certificate, Token authentication must be used.</li>
                            <li>The <codeph>uid</codeph> field used when generating the Token does not match the <codeph>uid</codeph> used when the user joins the channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errConnectionInterrupted</pt>
                    <pd>111: Network connection interrupted. SDK lost network connection for more than 4 seconds after establishing a connection with the server.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errConnectionLost</pt>
                    <pd>112: Network connection lost. The network was interrupted and the SDK could not reconnect to the server within 10 seconds.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errNotInChannel</pt>
                    <pd>113: User is not in the channel when calling the <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/> method.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errSizeTooLarge</pt>
                    <pd>114: The data length exceeds 1 KB when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errBitrateLimit</pt>
                    <pd>115: The data sending frequency exceeds the limit (6 KB/s) when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errTooManyDataStreams</pt>
                    <pd>116: The number of data streams created exceeds the limit (5) when calling <xref keyref="createDataStream2"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errStreamMessageTimeout</pt>
                    <pd>117: Data stream sending timed out.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errSetClientRoleNotAuthorized</pt>
                    <pd>119: Failed to switch user role. Please try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errDecryptionFailed</pt>
                    <pd>120: Media stream decryption failed. Possibly due to an incorrect key used when the user joined the channel. Please check the key entered when joining the channel or guide the user to try rejoining.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInvalidUserId</pt>
                    <pd>121: Invalid user ID.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errDatastreamDecryptionFailed</pt>
                    <pd>122: Data stream decryption failed. Possibly due to an incorrect key used when the user joined the channel. Please check the key entered when joining the channel or guide the user to try rejoining.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errClientIsBannedByServer</pt>
                    <pd>123: The user is banned by the server.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errEncryptedStreamNotAllowedPublish</pt>
                    <pd>130: The SDK does not support pushing encrypted streams to CDN.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errInvalidUserAccount</pt>
                    <pd>134: Invalid user account, possibly due to invalid parameters.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errPcmsendFormat</pt>
                    <pd>200: Unsupported PCM format.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errPcmsendBufferoverflow</pt>
                    <pd>201: Buffer overflow, PCM sending rate is too fast.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errLoadMediaEngine</pt>
                    <pd>1001: Failed to load media engine.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAdmGeneralError</pt>
                    <pd>1005: Audio device error (unspecified). Please check whether the audio device is occupied by another application, or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAdmInitPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1008: Error initializing playback device. Please check whether the playback device is occupied by another application, or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAdmStartPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1009: Error starting playback device. Please check whether the playback device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAdmStopPlayout</pt>
                    <pd>1010: Error stopping playback device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAdmInitRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1011: Error initializing recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly, or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAdmStartRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1012: Error starting recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errAdmStopRecording</pt>
                    <pd>1013: Error stopping recording device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="flutter">
                    <pt>errVdmCameraNotAuthorized</pt>
                    <pd>1501: No permission to use the camera. Please check whether camera permission is enabled.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_OK</pt>
                    <pd>0: No error.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_FAILED</pt>
                    <pd>1: A general error (no specific classification of the cause). Please try calling the method again.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INVALID_ARGUMENT</pt>
                    <pd>2: Invalid parameter set in the method. For example, the specified channel name contains illegal characters. Please reset the parameters.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_NOT_READY</pt>
                    <pd>3: SDK is not ready. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization failed. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>User has not joined the channel when calling the method. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>User has not left the channel when calling <xref keyref="rate"/> or <xref keyref="complain"/>. Please check the method call logic.</li>
                            <li>Audio module is not enabled.</li>
                            <li>Incomplete assembly.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_NOT_SUPPORTED</pt>
                    <pd>4: The current state of <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> does not support the operation. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>When using built-in encryption, the encryption mode is incorrect, or loading the external encryption library failed. Please check whether the encryption enum value is correct or reload the external encryption library.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_REFUSED</pt>
                    <pd>5: This method call was rejected. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li><xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization failed. Please reinitialize <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</li>
                            <li>Channel name is set to an empty string <codeph>""</codeph> when joining the channel. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                            <li>In multi-channel scenarios, the specified channel name already exists when calling <xref keyref="joinChannelEx"/>. Please reset the channel name.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_BUFFER_TOO_SMALL</pt>
                    <pd>6: Buffer size is insufficient to hold the returned data.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_NOT_INITIALIZED</pt>
                    <pd>7: <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> method called before initialization. Please ensure that the <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> object is created and initialized before calling the method.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INVALID_STATE</pt>
                    <pd>8: Invalid current state.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_NO_PERMISSION</pt>
                    <pd>9: No permission to operate. Please check whether the user has granted the app permission to use audio and video devices.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_TIMEDOUT</pt>
                    <pd>10: Method call timed out. Some method calls require a result from the SDK. If the SDK takes too long (over 10 seconds) to respond, this error occurs.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_JOIN_CHANNEL_REJECTED</pt>
                    <pd>17: Join channel request rejected. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>User is already in the channel. It is recommended to use the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback to determine whether the user is in the channel. Do not call this method again to join the channel unless receiving <codeph>CONNECTION_STATE_DISCONNECTED</codeph>(1).</li>
                            <li>After calling <xref keyref="startEchoTest3"/> for a call test, the user tries to join a channel without first calling <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> to end the test. You must call <xref keyref="stopEchoTest"/> before joining a channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_LEAVE_CHANNEL_REJECTED</pt>
                    <pd>18: Failed to leave the channel. Possible reasons include:
                        <ul>
                            <li>User has already left the channel before calling <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/>. You can stop calling this method.</li>
                            <li>User has not joined the channel but calls <xref keyref="leaveChannel2"/>. No additional action is required in this case.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ALREADY_IN_USE</pt>
                    <pd>19: Resource already in use and cannot be reused.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ABORTED</pt>
                    <pd>20: SDK aborted the request, possibly due to too many requests.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INIT_NET_ENGINE</pt>
                    <pd>21: On Windows, specific firewall settings cause <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/> initialization to fail and crash.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_RESOURCE_LIMITED</pt>
                    <pd>22: SDK failed to allocate resources, possibly due to excessive app resource usage or system resource exhaustion.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INVALID_APP_ID</pt>
                    <pd>101: Invalid App ID. Please use a valid App ID to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INVALID_CHANNEL_NAME</pt>
                    <pd>102: Invalid channel name. Possible reason is incorrect data type of the parameter. Please use a valid channel name to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_NO_SERVER_RESOURCES</pt>
                    <pd>103: Unable to acquire server resources in the current region. Try specifying a different region when initializing <xref keyref="IRtcEngine"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_TOKEN_EXPIRED</pt>
                    <pd>109: The current Token has expired and is no longer valid. Please request a new Token from the server and call <xref keyref="renewToken"/> to update it.
                        <note>Deprecated: This enum is deprecated. Use <codeph>CONNECTION_CHANGED_TOKEN_EXPIRED</codeph>(9) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INVALID_TOKEN</pt>
                    <pd>
                        <note>Deprecated: This enum is deprecated. Use <codeph>CONNECTION_CHANGED_INVALID_TOKEN</codeph>(8) in the <xref keyref="onConnectionStateChanged"/> callback instead.</note><ph>110: Invalid Token. Possible reasons include:</ph>
                        <ul>
                            <li>App certificate is enabled in the console, but App ID + Token authentication is not used. When the project enables the App certificate, Token authentication must be used.</li>
                            <li>The <codeph>uid</codeph> field used to generate the Token does not match the <codeph>uid</codeph> used when the user joins the channel.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_CONNECTION_INTERRUPTED</pt>
                    <pd>111: Network connection interrupted. SDK lost connection for more than 4 seconds after establishing a connection with the server.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_CONNECTION_LOST</pt>
                    <pd>112: Network connection lost. Connection interrupted and SDK fails to reconnect to the server within 10 seconds.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_NOT_IN_CHANNEL</pt>
                    <pd>113: User is not in the channel when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_SIZE_TOO_LARGE</pt>
                    <pd>114: Data length exceeds 1 KB when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_BITRATE_LIMIT</pt>
                    <pd>115: Data sending frequency exceeds the limit (6 KB/s) when calling <xref keyref="sendStreamMessage"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_TOO_MANY_DATA_STREAMS</pt>
                    <pd>116: Number of data streams exceeds the limit (5) when calling <xref keyref="createDataStream2"/>.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_STREAM_MESSAGE_TIMEOUT</pt>
                    <pd>117: Data stream sending timed out.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_SET_CLIENT_ROLE_NOT_AUTHORIZED</pt>
                    <pd>119: Failed to switch user role. Please try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_DECRYPTION_FAILED</pt>
                    <pd>120: Media stream decryption failed. Possibly due to incorrect key used when joining the channel. Please check the key entered when joining or guide the user to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INVALID_USER_ID</pt>
                    <pd>121: Invalid user ID.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_DATASTREAM_DECRYPTION_FAILED</pt>
                    <pd>122: Data stream decryption failed. Possibly due to incorrect key used when joining the channel. Please check the key entered when joining or guide the user to rejoin the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_CLIENT_IS_BANNED_BY_SERVER</pt>
                    <pd>123: This user is banned by the server.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ENCRYPTED_STREAM_NOT_ALLOWED_PUBLISH</pt>
                    <pd>130: SDK does not support publishing encrypted streams to CDN.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_INVALID_USER_ACCOUNT</pt>
                    <pd>134: Invalid user account, possibly due to invalid parameters.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_LOAD_MEDIA_ENGINE</pt>
                    <pd>1001: Failed to load media engine.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_PCMSEND_FORMAT</pt>
                    <pd>200: Unsupported PCM format.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_PCMSEND_BUFFEROVERFLOW</pt>
                    <pd>201: Buffer overflow due to PCM send rate being too fast.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ADM_GENERAL_ERROR</pt>
                    <pd>1005: Audio device error (unspecified). Please check whether the audio device is occupied by another application or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ADM_INIT_PLAYOUT</pt>
                    <pd>1008: Error initializing playback device. Please check whether the playback device is occupied by another application or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ADM_START_PLAYOUT</pt>
                    <pd>1009: Error starting playback device. Please check whether the playback device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ADM_STOP_PLAYOUT</pt>
                    <pd>1010: Error stopping playback device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ADM_INIT_RECORDING</pt>
                    <pd>1011: Error initializing recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly or try rejoining the channel.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ADM_START_RECORDING</pt>
                    <pd>1012: Error starting recording device. Please check whether the recording device is functioning properly.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_ADM_STOP_RECORDING</pt>
                    <pd>1013: Error stopping recording device.</pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry props="unity">
                    <pt>ERR_VDM_CAMERA_NOT_AUTHORIZED</pt>
                    <pd>1501: No permission to use the camera. Please check whether camera access is enabled.</pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>