<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="release_notes">
    <title>v4.5.1</title>
    <body>
        <p>v4.5.1 was released on March 3, 2025.</p>
    </body>
    <topic id="level2">
        <title/>
        <topic id="compatibility">
            <title>Compatibility changes</title>
            <body>
             <note type="attention" props="native">
             <ul>
             <li>自 4.5.0 起，RTC SDK 和 RTM SDK (2.2.0 及以上版本) 都包含 <codeph props="android">libaosl.so</codeph><codeph props="cpp">libaosl.dll</codeph><codeph props="apple">aosl.xcframework</codeph> 库。 If you manually integrate Video SDK via CDN and also use Signaling SDK, delete the earlier version of the <codeph props="android"><codeph props="apple">libaosl.so </codeph><codeph props="cpp">library</codeph> to avoid conflicts.</codeph></li>
             <li>4.5.1 RTC SDK <codeph props="android">libaosl.so</codeph><codeph props="cpp">libaosl.dll</codeph><codeph props="apple">aosl.xcframework</codeph> 库版本为 xxx。 <ph props="apple">你可以在 <codeph>Info.plist</codeph> 中查看库的版本信息。 </ph><ph props="cpp">你可以通过查看 <codeph>libaosl.dll</codeph> 文件的属性来得知库的版本信息。</ph></li></ul>
             </note>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="newfeature">
            <title>New features</title>
            <body>
                <ol>
                    <li><ph><b>AI conversation scenario</b></ph><p>This version adds the <codeph><ph keyref="AUDIO_SCENARIO_AI_CLIENT"/></codeph> audio scenario specifically designed for interacting with the conversational AI agent created by <xref keyref="convoai"/>. This scenario optimizes the audio transmission algorithm based on the characteristics of AI agent voice generation, ensuring stable voice data transmission in weak network environments (for example, 80% packet loss rate), and ensuring the continuity and reliability of the conversation, adapting to a variety of complex network conditions.</p>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="improvement">
            <title>Improvements</title>
            <body>
                <ol>
                    <li props="ios cpp unity flutter rn">Reduced the time of initializing the SDK on specific device models.<ph props="cpp unity flutter rn"> (iOS)</ph></li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="bugfix">
            <title>Issues fixed</title>
            <body>
                <p>This release fixed the following issues:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter rn android">Apps that integrated the Agora SDK and set the <codeph>targetSdkVersion</codeph> to 34 encountered crashes when attempting to enable screen sharing for the first time on an Android 14 system. (Android)<ph props="cpp unity flutter rn"></ph></li>
                    <li>When joining two or more channels simultaneously, and calling the <codeph><apiname keyref="takeSnapshotEx"/></codeph> method to take screenshots of the local video streams in each channel consecutively, the screenshot of the first channel failed.</li>
                    <li>When using the <codeph><apiname keyref="pause"/></codeph> method to pause playback, then calling <codeph><apiname keyref="seek"/></codeph> to move to a specified position, and finally calling <codeph><apiname keyref="play"/></codeph> to continue playback, the Media Player resumed from the position where it was paused, not the new specified position.</li>
                    <li>When using the Media Player, the file path of the media resource returned by the <codeph><apiname keyref="getPlaySrc"/></codeph> did not change after calling the <codeph><apiname keyref="switchSrc"/></codeph> method to switch to a new media resource.</li>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter rn android">When using Bluetooth headphones on specific device models for audio and video interactions, adjusting the phone volume would occassionally change the media volume instead of the Bluetooth volume. <ph props="cpp unity flutter rn">(Android)</ph></li>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter rn android">During audio and video interactions, the local user occasionally experienced a black screen when watching the video streams of remote users. <ph props="cpp unity flutter rn">(Android)</ph></li>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter rn android">On specific models of device, after calling <codeph><apiname keyref="setCameraExposureFactor"/></codeph> to set the exposure coefficient of the current camera at a specific angle of the device, the video screen occasionally became dark when the device was moved to another angle. (Android)<ph props="cpp unity flutter rn"></ph></li>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter rn android">When playing a CDN live stream, the video occasionally froze for an extended period after recovering from an interruption. <ph props="cpp unity flutter rn">(Android)</ph></li>
                    <li props="ios cpp unity flutter rn">When pushing video frames in i420 format to the channel, using CVPixelBuffer to handle these frames caused a crash.<ph props="cpp unity flutter rn"> (iOS)</ph></li>
                    <li props="ios cpp unity flutter rn">Calling <codeph><apiname keyref="setupLocalVideo"/></codeph> to set up two views, then calling <codeph><apiname keyref="enableFaceDetection"/></codeph> to start face detection, no face information can be detected in the subsequently passed views.<ph props="cpp unity flutter rn"> (iOS)</ph></li>
                    <li props="ios cpp unity flutter rn">In a screen sharing scenario, the receiving-end user saw a green line on the shared image.<ph props="cpp unity flutter rn"> (iOS)</ph></li>
                    <li>In the interactive live streaming scenario, after joining a channel to watch live streams using <codeph>string</codeph> user id, the audience members occasionally saw that the audio was not synchronized with the video.</li>
                    <li>Plugins sometimes did not work when using AI noise suppression and AI echo cancellation plugins at the same time.</li>
                </ul>
            </body>
        </topic>
    </topic>
</topic>
