<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="release-notes">
    <title>v4.2.3</title>
    <body>
        <p>v4.2.3 was released on September xx, 2023.</p>
    </body>
    <topic id="level2">
        <title/>
        <topic id="newfeature">
            <title>New features</title>
            <body>
                <ol>
                    <li><ph><b>Update video screenshot and upload</b></ph><p><ph>To facilitate the integration of third-party video moderation services from Agora Extensions Marketplace, this version has the following changes:</ph><ul>
                                <li props="cpp apple unity rn flutter">The <codeph><apiname keyref="CONTENT_INSPECT_IMAGE_MODERATION"/></codeph> enumeration is added in <codeph><apiname keyref="CONTENT_INSPECT_TYPE"/></codeph> which means using video moderation extensions from Agora Extensions Marketplace to take video screenshots and upload them.</li>
                                <li props="android">The <codeph><apiname keyref="CONTENT_INSPECT_IMAGE_MODERATION"/></codeph> enumeration is added in the <codeph>type</codeph> parameter of <codeph><apiname keyref="ContentInspectModule"/></codeph>, which means using video moderation extensions from Agora Extensions Marketplace to take video screenshots and upload them.</li>
                                <li>An optional parameter <codeph>serverConfig</codeph> is added in <codeph><apiname keyref="ContentInspectConfig"/></codeph>, which is for server-side configuration related to video screenshot and upload via extensions from Agora Extensions Marketplace. By configuring this parameter, you can integrate multiple third-party moderation extensions and achieve flexible control over extension switches and other features. For more details, please contact <ph keyref="ticket-link"/>.</li>
                            </ul><ph>In addition, this version also introduces the <codeph><apiname keyref="enableContentInspectEx"/></codeph> method, which supports taking screenshots for multiple video streams and uploading them.</ph></p>
                    </li>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter electron"><ph><b>ID3D11Texture2D Rendering</b></ph> (Windows)<p>As of this release, the SDK supports video formats of type ID3D11Texture2D, improving the rendering effect of video frames in game scenarios. You can set <codeph>format</codeph> to <codeph>VIDEO_TEXTURE_ID3D11TEXTURE2D</codeph> when pushing external raw video frames to the SDK by calling <codeph><apiname keyref="pushVideoFrame"/></codeph>. By setting the <codeph>d3d11_texture_2d</codeph> and <codeph>texture_slice_index</codeph> properties, you can determine the ID3D11Texture2D texture object to use.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter electron"><ph><b>Local video status error code update</b></ph> (Windows, macOS)<p>In order to help users understand the exact reasons for local video errors in screen sharing scenarios, the following sets of enumerations have been added to the <codeph><apiname keyref="onLocalVideoStateChanged"/></codeph> callback:<ul>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_PAUSED"/></codeph>(23): Screen capture has been paused. Common scenarios for reporting this error code: The current screen may have been switched to a secure desktop, such as a UAC dialog box or Winlogon desktop.</li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_RESUMED"/></codeph>(24): Screen capture has resumed from the paused state.</li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_HIDDEN"/></codeph>(25): The window being captured on the current screen is in a hidden state and is not visible on the current screen.</li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_RECOVER_FROM_HIDDEN"/></codeph>(26): The window for screen capture has been restored from the hidden state.</li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_RECOVER_FROM_MINIMIZED"/></codeph>(27): The window for screen capture has been restored from the minimized state.</li>
                        </ul></p>
                    </li>
                    <li><ph><b>Check device support for advanced features</b></ph><p>This version adds the <codeph><apiname keyref="isFeatureAvailableOnDevice"/></codeph> method to check whether the capability of the current device meets the requirements of the specified advanced feature, such as virtual background and image enhancement. </p>
                        <p>Before using advanced features, you can check whether the current device supports these features based on the call result. This helps to avoid performance degradation or unavailable features when enabling advanced features on low-end devices. Based on the return value of this method, you can decide whether to display or enable the corresponding feature button, or notify the user when the device's capabilities are insufficient.</p>
                        <p>In addition, since this version, calling <codeph><apiname keyref="enableVirtualBackground"/></codeph> and <codeph><apiname keyref="setBeautyEffectOptions"/></codeph> automatically triggers a test on the capability of the current device. When the device is considered underperformed, the error code <codeph> -4:<ph keyref="ERR_NOT_SUPPORTED"/></codeph> is returned, indicating the device does not support the feature.</p>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="improvement">
            <title>Improvements</title>
            <body>
                <ol>
                    <li><ph><b>Optimize virtual background memory usage</b></ph><p>This version has upgraded the virtual background algorithm, reducing the memory usage of the virtual background feature.  Compared to the previous version, the memory consumption of the app during the use of the virtual background feature on low-end devices has been reduced by approximately 4% to 10% (specific values may vary depending on the device model and platform).</p>
                    </li>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter electron android"><ph><b>Screen sharing scenario optimization</b></ph><p props="cpp unity flutter electron">This release optimizes the performance and encoding efficiency in ultra-high-definition (4K, 60 fps) game sharing scenarios, effectively reducing the system resource usage during screen sharing.</p>
                        <p props="android">This release also optimizes the video encoding configuration in screen sharing scenarios. When users customize the <codeph>width</codeph> and <codeph>height</codeph> properties of the video, the SDK rounds down the actual encoding resolution while maintaining the aspect ratio of the video and the screen, ensuring that the final encoding resolution does not exceed the user-defined encoding resolution, thereby improving the accuracy of billing for screen sharing streams.</p>
                    </li>
                </ol>
                <p><b>Other Improvements</b></p>
                <p>This release includes the following additional improvements:<ul>
                    <li props="android">Optimizes the management method of Texture Buffer for SDK capture and custom video capture scenarios, effectively eliminating frame dropping and crash risks.</li>
                     <li>Optimizes the logic of handling invalid parameters. When you call the <codeph><apiname keyref="setPlaybackSpeed"/></codeph> method to set the playback speed of audio files, if you pass an invalid parameter, the SDK returns the error code -2, which means that you need to reset the parameter.</li>
                     <li>Optimizes the logic of Token parsing, in order to prevent an app from crash when an invalid token is passed in.</li>
                    </ul></p>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="bugfix">
            <title>Issues fixed</title>
            <body>
                <p>This release fixed the following issues:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter electron">Occasional crashes and dropped frames occured in screen sharing scenarios. (Windows)</li>
                    <li props="android">When using the H.265 encoding mode, when a Web client joined the interactivity, it caused a redundant <codeph><apiname keyref="onUserEnableLocalVideo"/></codeph> callback on the native side: when the host called <codeph><apiname keyref="enableLocalVideo"/> (true)</codeph>, the receiving end first received a <codeph><apiname keyref="onUserEnableLocalVideo"/></codeph> callback (with <codeph>enabled</codeph> as <codeph>false</codeph>) before receiving a <codeph><apiname keyref="onUserEnableLocalVideo"/></codeph> callback (with <codeph>enabled</codeph> as <codeph>true</codeph>).</li>
                    <li props="mac unity flutter electron"><p><ph>Occasional crashes when joining a channel. </ph><ph>(macOS)</ph></p></li>
                    <li>Occasional failure of joining a channel when the local system time was not set correctly.</li>
                    <li>When calling the <codeph><apiname keyref="playEffect3"></apiname></codeph> method to play two audio files using the same <codeph>soundId</codeph>, the first audio file was somtimes played repeatedly.</li>
                    <li props="android unity flutter rn"><p><ph>When the host called the <codeph><apiname keyref="startAudioMixing2"/></codeph> method to play music, sometimes the host couldn't hear the music while the remote users could hear it. </ph><ph props="unity flutter rn">(Android)</ph></p></li>
                    <li props="android ios unity flutter rn"><p><ph>In a chorus scenario, calling the <codeph><apiname keyref="preload"/></codeph> method to load music sometimes failed. </ph><ph props="unity flutter">(Android, iOS)</ph></p></li>
                    <li props="android unity flutter rn"><p><ph>Occasional crashes occured on certain Android devices. </ph><ph props="unity flutter rn">(Android)</ph></p></li>
                    <li props="android ios unity flutter rn"><p><ph>Loading music lists failed when the local system time was not correct. </ph><ph props="unity flutter">(Android, iOS)</ph></p></li>
                    <li>Calling <codeph><apiname keyref="takeSnapshotEx"/></codeph> once receives the <codeph><apiname keyref="onSnapshotTaken"/></codeph> callback for multiple times. </li>
                    <li props="android unity flutter rn"><p><ph>In channels joined by calling <codeph><apiname keyref="joinChannelEx"/></codeph> exclusively, calling <codeph><apiname keyref="setEnableSpeakerphone"/></codeph> is unable to switch audio route from the speaker to the headphone. </ph><ph props="unity flutter rn">(Android)</ph></p></li>
                </ul>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="apichange">
            <title>API changes</title>
            <body>
                <p><b>Added</b><ul>
                    <li props="cpp unity flutter electron">The following enumerations in <codeph><apiname keyref="onLocalVideoStateChanged"/></codeph>: (Windows, macOS)<ul>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_PAUSED"/></codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_RESUMED"/></codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_HIDDEN"/></codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_RECOVER_FROM_HIDDEN"/></codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph><apiname keyref="LOCAL_VIDEO_STREAM_ERROR_SCREEN_CAPTURE_WINDOW_RECOVER_FROM_MINIMIZED"/></codeph></li>
                        </ul></li>
                    <li  props="cpp unity flutter electron"><codeph>d3d11_texture_2d</codeph> and <codeph>texture_slice_index</codeph> members in .<codeph><apiname keyref="ExternalVideoFrame"/></codeph></li> 
                    <li  props="cpp unity flutter electron"><codeph><apiname keyref="VIDEO_PIXEL_FORMAT"/></codeph>中新增 <codeph><apiname keyref="VIDEO_TEXTURE_ID3D11TEXTURE2D"/></codeph> 枚举 (Windows)</li> 
                    <li><codeph><apiname keyref="enableContentInspectEx"/></codeph></li>
                    <li props="cpp apple rn unity flutter"><codeph><apiname keyref="CONTENT_INSPECT_IMAGE_MODERATION"/></codeph> in <codeph><apiname keyref="CONTENT_INSPECT_TYPE"/></codeph>.</li>
                    <li props="android"><codeph><apiname keyref="CONTENT_INSPECT_IMAGE_MODERATION"/></codeph> in <codeph>type</codeph> of <codeph><apiname keyref="ContentInspectModule"/></codeph>.</li>
                    <li><codeph>serverConfig</codeph> in <codeph><apiname keyref="ContentInspectConfig"/></codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph><apiname keyref="isFeatureAvailableOnDevice"/></codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph><apiname keyref="FeatureType"/></codeph></li>
                    </ul></p>
            </body>
        </topic>
    </topic>
</topic>
