<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd">
<reference id="api_irtcengine_startlocalvideotranscoder">
    <title><ph keyref="startLocalVideoTranscoder" /></title>
    <shortdesc id="short"><ph id="shortdesc">Starts the local video mixing.</ph></shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
                <indexterm keyref="startLocalVideoTranscoder" />
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <refbody>
        <section id="prototype">
            <p outputclass="codeblock">
            <codeblock props="android" outputclass="language-java">public abstract int startLocalVideoTranscoder(LocalTranscoderConfiguration config);</codeblock>
            <codeblock props="ios mac" outputclass="language-objectivec">- (int)startLocalVideoTranscoder:(AgoraLocalTranscoderConfiguration* _Nonnull)config NS_SWIFT_NAME(startLocalVideoTranscoder(_:));</codeblock>
            <codeblock props="cpp" outputclass="language-cpp">virtual int startLocalVideoTranscoder(const LocalTranscoderConfiguration&amp; config) = 0;
</codeblock>
            <codeblock props="electron" outputclass="language-typescript">abstract startLocalVideoTranscoder(
    config: LocalTranscoderConfiguration
  ): number;</codeblock>
            <codeblock props="unity" outputclass="language-csharp">public abstract int StartLocalVideoTranscoder(LocalTranscoderConfiguration config);</codeblock>
            <codeblock props="rn" outputclass="language-typescript">abstract startLocalVideoTranscoder(
    config: LocalTranscoderConfiguration
  ): number;</codeblock>
            <codeblock props="flutter" outputclass="language-dart">Future&lt;void&gt; startLocalVideoTranscoder(LocalTranscoderConfiguration config);</codeblock>
            <codeblock props="reserve" outputclass="language-cpp"></codeblock></p>
        </section>
        <section id="detailed_desc">
            <title>Details</title>
            <p>After calling this method, you can merge multiple video streams into one video stream locally. For example, you can merge the video streams captured by the camera, screen sharing, media player, remote video, video files, images, etc. into one video stream, and then publish the mixed video stream to the channel.</p>
                <note>
                <ul>
                    <li>Local video mixing requires more CPU resources. Therefore, Agora recommends enabling this function on devices with higher performance.</li>
                    <li>If you need to mix locally captured video streams, the SDK supports the following capture combinations:<ul>
                        <li props="cpp">On the Windows platform, it supports up to 4 video streams captured by cameras + 4 screen sharing streams.</li>
                        <li props="cpp mac">On the macOS platform, it supports up to 4 video streams captured by cameras + 1 screen sharing stream.</li>
                        <li props="cpp">On Android and iOS platforms, it supports video streams captured by up to 2 cameras (the device itself needs to support dual cameras or supports external cameras) + 1 screen sharing stream.</li>
                        <li props="android">On the Android platform, it supports up to 2 video streams captured by cameras (the device itself needs to support dual cameras or support external cameras) + 1 screen sharing stream.</li>
                        <li props="ios">On the iOS platform, it supports up to 2 video streams captured by cameras (the device itself needs to support dual cameras or support external cameras) + 1 screen sharing stream.</li></ul></li>
                    <li>If you need to mix the locally collected video streams, you need to call this method after <xref keyref="startCameraCapture"/> or <xref props="cpp mac unity flutter electron unreal" keyref="startScreenCapture2"/><xref props="ios android rn" keyref="startScreenCapture"/>.</li> 
                    <li>If you want to publish the mixed video stream to the channel, you need to set <parmname>publishTranscodedVideoTrack</parmname> in <xref keyref="ChannelMediaOptions"/> to <codeph><ph keyref="true"/></codeph> when calling <xref keyref="joinChannel2"/> or <xref keyref="updateChannelMediaOptions"/>.</li></ul>
                </note>
        </section>
        <section id="scenario">
        <title>Applicable scenarios</title>
        <p>You can enable the local video mixing function in scenarios such as remote conferences, live streaming, and online education, which allows users to view and manage multiple videos more conveniently, and supports portrait Picture in Picture mode and other functions.</p>
        <p>The following is a typical use case for implementing portrait Picture in Picture scenario:<ol>
                <li>Call <xref keyref="enableVirtualBackground"/>, and set the custom background image to <apiname keyref="BACKGROUND_NONE"/>, that is, separate the portrait and the background in the video captured by the camera.</li>
                <li>调用 <xref props="cpp mac unity flutter electron unreal" keyref="startScreenCapture2"/><xref props="ios android rn" keyref="startScreenCapture"/>，开始采集屏幕共享视频流。</li>
                <li>调用该方法，并将采集人像的视频源设置为参与本地合图的视频源之一，即可在合图后的视频中实现人像画中画。
                    <note>在进行合图配置时，需确保采集人像的摄像头视频流在合图中的图层编号大于屏幕共享流的图层编号，否则人像会被屏幕共享覆盖、无法显示在最终合图的视频流中。</note></li>
                </ol></p>
        </section>
        <section id="parameters">
            <title>Parameters</title>
            <parml>
            <plentry>
                <pt>config</pt>
                <pd>Configuration of the local video mixing, see <xref keyref="LocalTranscoderConfiguration" />.<note type="attention"><ul>
                <li>The maximum resolution of each video stream participating in the local video mixing is 4096 × 2160. If this limit is exceeded, video mixing does not take effect.</li>
                <li>合图后的视频流最大分辨率为 4096 × 2160。</li></ul></note></pd>
            </plentry>
            </parml> </section>
        <section id="return_values">
            <title><ph keyref="return-section-title"/></title>
            <p props="flutter">When the method call succeeds, there is no return value; when fails, the <xref keyref="AgoraRtcException"/> exception is thrown; you need to catch the exception and handle it accordingly.</p>
            <ul id="ul_ahk_23f_3qb">
            <li props="native electron unity rn">0: Success.</li>
            <li>&lt; 0: Failure.</li>
            </ul> </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
